{"Topic": "International Organisations", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade was replaced by -", "op1": "North American Free Trade Association", "op2": "South Asian Free Trade Association", "op3": "World Trade Organisation", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of these organisations has been awarded the Nobel Peace Prize three times?", "op1": "International Committee of the Red Cross", "op2": "Amnesty International", "op3": "Transparency International", "op4": "United Nations Organisation", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following organisations works towards ending grave abuses of human rights?", "op1": "International Red Cross", "op2": "United Nations Organisation", "op3": "Transparency International", "op4": "Amnesty International", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following publishes the Red List of Threatened Species?", "op1": "UNEP", "op2": "WWF", "op3": "IUCN", "op4": "WNO", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "India is a not a member of which of the following organisations?", "op1": "Commonwealth of Nations", "op2": "ASEAN", "op3": "Indian Ocean Rim Association", "op4": "South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of these organisations releases the Annual Corruption Perception Index ranking of countries by their perceived levels of corruption?", "op1": "Transparency International", "op2": "WIPO", "op3": "World Trade Organisation", "op4": "World Bank"}, {"Question": "Which of the following organisations gives a call for Earth Hour to be observed on the last Saturday of March every year?", "op1": "Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change", "op2": "Worldwide Fund for Nature", "op3": "Greenpeace International", "op4": "International Renewable Energy Agency", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following organisations gives away the Crystal Award to artists who have used their art to improve the state of the world?", "op1": "World Economic Forum", "op2": "UNESCO", "op3": "Worldwide Fund for Nature", "op4": "Food and Agricultural Organisations"}, {"Question": "Which of these organizations was initially set up as 'Atoms for Peace' organization in 1957?", "op1": "World Nuclear Association", "op2": "Greenpeace", "op3": "North Atlantic Treaty Organisation", "op4": "International Atomic Energy Agency", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which two South American countries are part of OPEC (Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries)?", "op1": "Columbia and Venezuela", "op2": "Ecuador and Angola", "op3": "Ecuador and Venezuela", "op4": "Peru and Chile", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who was the Prime Minister of India when South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) was established?", "op1": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op2": "PV Narsimha Rao", "op3": "IK Gujral", "op4": "HD Deve Gowda", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of these organizations was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for the year 2013?", "op1": "Amnesty International", "op2": "Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons", "op3": "International Renewable Energy Agency", "op4": "International Red Cross"}, {"Question": "Which organization was formed by Henry Dunant the winner of the first Nobel Peace prize in 1901?", "op1": "Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons", "op2": "Worldwide Fund for Nature", "op3": "M\u00e9decins Sans Fronti\u00e8res", "op4": "International Red Cross", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which three nations have signed a treaty to establish economic union called Eurasian Economic Union by 2015?", "op1": "Russia, Ukraine and Kazakhstan", "op2": "Tajikistan, Belarus and Kazakhstan", "op3": "Russia, Belarus and Kazakhstan", "op4": "Armenia, Russia and Belarus", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which African nation is NOT a member of the African Union?", "op1": "Algeria", "op2": "Morocco", "op3": "Lesotho", "op4": "Comoros", "Answer": 2}]}